applyboard.com 2016-10-13

# Privacy Policy | ApplyBoard

  1. [Home](https://www.applyboard.com/home)
  2. **Privacy Policy**

At Easy Education Inc. (“EasyEducation” or “ApplyBoard”), your right to privacy is very important to us.  We provide you with the ability to investigate the process of becoming a student at certain educational institutions within Canada and the U.S., including information respecting visa applications and program information, and the ability to apply for admission to certain programs of such institutions through our website.  In order to provide you with this service effectively, we collect certain specific information from you, and we also automatically collect information and data relating to the usage of our services by all our users, including you. Because we are committed to protecting your privacy rights and the information you provide to us, we have developed this privacy policy. It explains how we will protect your information and describes how we will use and share it. 

This policy is concerned with the protection of your personal information only. Personal information includes any data that can be used to identify you as an individual, including your name, income, personal opinion, interests, home contact information, identification numbers, user IDs, passwords, ethnic origin, and age. Under Canadian law, in a business context, personal information does not include the name, job title, business address, or business telephone number of any employee in an organization.   

This policy describes the following practices:

  * Collecting information

  * Sharing your personal information

  * Maintaining your personal information

This privacy policy may change from time to time to reflect ApplyBoard’s internal needs, customer feedback, or changes in applicable privacy legislation. ApplyBoard will post all such changes on our website, so please visit this page regularly.   

NOTE:  ApplyBoard services are not intended for children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect or maintain any personal information or non-personally-identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 nor is any part of our website or services directed to children under the age of 13. We will close any accounts used exclusively by such children and will remove and/or delete any personal information we believe was submitted by any child under the age of 13.

##  Collecting information

In order to use the services provided by ApplyBoard, you will be required to provide specific information about yourself, such as your name, address, telephone number and educational background.  We will inform you when we need information that personally identifies you, and we will keep this information in strict confidence, using such information only to the extent necessary to provide our services to you (which may include disclosing such information to educational and other institutions as part of your application for admittance).  Additionally, you may, on occasion, voluntarily provide ApplyBoard with information that can be classified as personal information – all such personal information will be stored and maintained in accordance with this privacy policy.  

We collect information about you in the following ways:   

###  As part of your registration for ApplyBoard’s services

We will require your name, address, telephone number and payment information for billing purposes, and all information required for your application to your selected educational institution, and you will also be provided with a user ID and a password, or the ability to create a user ID and/or password.  This information is kept confidential and stored securely by ApplyBoard.  

###  Automatically by ApplyBoard’s software and services

ApplyBoard’s services contain features that automatically collect information from users, such as viewing times, usage statistics, and other tracking information – this information may be specific to your individual usage, or may be general and not connected with your personal identification.  Additionally, use of ApplyBoard’s web portal may result in the collection of technical information such as your computer's IP address, operating system, browser name/version, the referring web page, requested page, date/time, and sometimes a "cookie" (which can be disabled using your browser preferences); such information is used to help us understand the overall usage pattern of our website and software.  

###  As part of your use of ApplyBoard’s services

You will have the ability to fill out forms, on a voluntary basis, related to your application to educational institutions through our website.  Although your provision of information through these forms is voluntary, failure to provide the information will likely result in an incomplete application to the applicable educational institution, and will therefore result in additional costs to you and/or automatic rejection of your application.  All such information shall, nevertheless, be kept in strict confidence by ApplyBoard, stored securely, and used by ApplyBoard only to the extent necessary to provide our services to you.  Once ApplyBoard has provided your information to educational institutions for your application for admittance, ApplyBoard does not have any control over the use of such information by educational institutions or any third party obtaining access to the information through the educational institutions, and you must deal with such persons directly respecting any unauthorized use of your personal information.  

You may have the ability to post information through ApplyBoard’s services, such as questions, comments and opinions.  Please be advised that any personal information that you voluntarily post to any public forum or to any area where third parties may legally access it, will NOT be considered confidential in any way, and ApplyBoard will not have any obligation to protect it in a secured system or obtain your consent to its disclosure, as you will have made the decision to publicly post it.  However, at your request, ApplyBoard will be happy to change it, remove it, or restrict access to it (subject to technical feasibility) in order to protect the integrity of the personal information.  

###  You contact ApplyBoard directly  

Users sometimes contact us directly. When you contact any ApplyBoard employee by telephone, e-mail, in person, or through our website, you will be asked to provide consent to the collection of personal information if your personal information will help us deliver the information or services you require. Notwithstanding the foregoing, by providing personal information to ApplyBoard in the course of making any unsolicited request of ApplyBoard, you acknowledge that your consent has been tacitly provided to ApplyBoard to use your personal information in relation to such request and in accordance with this privacy policy.  

###  You respond to communications from ApplyBoard

From time to time, ApplyBoard may invite you to provide us with information for specific purposes.  We may ask for this information through feedback features on our website or software; we may send out e-mail inviting feedback or offering products and services; or we may ask you for information concerning support of our products or services. Your response to these communications may require you to submit personal information and opinions.  

###  Your information is obtained through a third party

Occasionally, ApplyBoard will obtain information about you from third parties, such as mailing list providers, third party service providers, ISPs, or third party application or account providers. Third-party providers are responsible for obtaining consent for the release of personal information to us from those individuals identified on mailing lists, surveys, or through other collection methods.

##  Sharing your personal information

Subject to any exceptions stated above in the collection of information section, should ApplyBoard collect any of your personal information, we will follow these practices regarding the distribution of that information.   

###  Your personal information is always protected

ApplyBoard uses reasonable precautions to protect your personal information and store it securely. Access to your personal information is restricted to those personnel who need it, and ApplyBoard takes reasonable steps to prevent the unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal information. 

ApplyBoard only uses and discloses your personal information for the purpose providing you with the services, if it helps us facilitate your needs, improve our products and services, meet legal and regulatory requirements, or — to the limited extent possible — manage our internal business operations.  Additionally, if there are any disclosure or use restrictions in your consent to the collection of your personal information, ApplyBoard will abide by those restrictions (subject to the consent exceptions listed below).  

ApplyBoard may combine your information with other information into an aggregate form, so your information no longer personally identifies you. We may then disclose the aggregate information to third parties, so they can obtain an overall picture of ApplyBoard’s services, geographic demand and/or usage patterns.   

###  We only share your information with your consent

ApplyBoard provides your information to third parties only for purposes to which you have consented, and we require such third parties to keep your information confidential. You acknowledge that the purpose of the services is for you to apply to study at certain educational institutions within Canada and the US; accordingly, by using the services, you consent to our provision of your personal information (including your name, educational information, information input by you on application forms through our site, access statistics and other usage information) to such educational and other institutions (such as applicable governmental authorities) for the purpose of furthering your application to study at such institutions within Canada and the US.  You further acknowledge that your such institutions’ and authorities’ use of such information will be in accordance with the usage rights as agreed upon between you and such institutions and authorities, and subject to the laws of the jurisdiction within which the institutions are located.  

In a few situations, ApplyBoard may be required to disclose your information without your prior consent. For example, ApplyBoard may disclose your information if we are required to do so by law, or if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to: 

  * comply with law or legal process

  * protect and defend our rights and property, or the rights and property of a third party

  * protect against misuse or unauthorized use of any of ApplyBoard’s services or other proprietary materials

  * protect the personal safety of any person

  * allow for a change of ownership of ApplyBoard and associated transfer of all personal information to the new owner of ApplyBoard – this does not affect the protection of your information under this Privacy Policy  

ApplyBoard will always try to provide you with prior notice of such disclosure; however, such notice may not always be possible or reasonable given the circumstances.

##  Maintaining your personal information

ApplyBoard has established the following practices regarding the maintenance of your personal information.    

###  You can request access to your personal information at any time

If, for any reason, you wish to review your personal information that ApplyBoard has in its possession, you can contact our Privacy Officer, who will be pleased to provide you with all your personal information that ApplyBoard has on file.  

###  You can request changes to your personal information at any time

Sometimes, it will be necessary for you to update your personal information ApplyBoard has on file. For example, if you move or change payment information, you must update your information in order to keep receiving the services provided by ApplyBoard.  If you wish to make any changes or corrections to your personal information, please contact our Privacy Officer who will implement the changes. This will help us ensure our records are always up-to-date.  

###  You can opt out of communications at any time

Additionally, you always have the choice of whether you wish to receive information – such as e-mail updates – from ApplyBoard.  If you do choose to opt out of communications respecting products and services provided by ApplyBoard, you may not obtain all the benefits we could otherwise provide, such as updates or warnings. ApplyBoard will not have any liability to you for your loss of those benefits or any negative effects respecting your use of ApplyBoard’s products or services.  

###  You can request that your personal information be destroyed at any time

A situation may arise where you desire to have all of your personal information that is contained in ApplyBoard’s records deleted or destroyed.  If this is what you wish, please contact our Privacy Officer, who will take care of removing your personal information from all of ApplyBoard’s records.  However, there may be situations where we are obligated to retain one archival copy of your information to allow us to comply with laws or respond to legal processes.  We will inform you of all such situations, and will only use your retained personal information to the limited extent necessary to comply with such laws or respond to legal processes.

##  Contacting our Privacy Officer  

ApplyBoard welcomes your comments about this privacy policy, and we would be happy to provide any additional information you require. Please contact our Privacy Officer at:   

or  

Easy Education Inc

Suite 1100, 30 Duke St. West, Kitchener, Ontario, Canada N2H 3W5

+1 519 900 6001   

This privacy policy supplements any agreements you already have with ApplyBoard, such as the Usage Terms. Our privacy policy does not replace the terms of those agreements. By agreeing to those terms and using ApplyBoard’s website and services, you are consenting to the collection and use of your personal information by ApplyBoard in accordance with this privacy policy. This policy was written in accordance with the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA).
